

# Calin Oliverio

User Experience Designer

Rotterdam, NL

Website

in LinkedIn

Be Behance

### **Profile**

User Experience Designer, based in the Netherlands, with an architectural background. Planned and designed 25+ housing and commercial projects that varied in size and have now traded buildings for prototypes. Great at organizing complex data into digestible pieces and crafting pixel perfect prototypes.

### **UX Skills**

Competitive Analysis Generative & Evaluative Research Information Architecture User Flows/Journeys Sketching Mobile-First & Responsive Design Iterative Wireframing & Prototyping User-Centered Design Usability & Preference Testing

## Soft Skills

Client Communication Critical Analysis Problem-Solving Self-Motivation Decisiveness Negotiation

# Tools

Adobe XD Invision Balsamiq FlowMapp Adobe CS CSS HTML JavaScript

## Languages

English - native Dutch - A2/B1

### Hobbies

Hiking Snowboarding Pottery Drawing Cooking (I will bring cookies to the office) Carpentry

### Education

#### PROFESSIONAL UX DESIGN CERTICATION

CareerFoundry Rotterdam, NL May 2020 - Jan 2021

Intensive training program for UX Designers, specializing in UX process and methodology that includes user research, user journeys, user personas, testing, information architecture, and visual design fundamentals.

- Designed 2 mobile first apps using software such as InVision, Adobe XD, and Balsamiq
- Designed and coded a website using HTML, CSS, and Javascript

#### MASTERS OF ARCHITECTURE

University of Colorado Aug 2016 - Dec 2018 Denver, USA

Community and user-centered design studies focused on research and analysis on the human and built systems in our environment.

#### BACHELORS OF ENVIRONMENTAL DESIGN IN ARCHITECTURE

North Carolina State University Raleigh, USA Aug 2011 - May 2015

Design foundations based on Black College and Bauhaus principles, where design thinking and critical analysis were heavily emphasized.

### **UX/UI Experience**

### WEBSITE DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT

Rotterdam, NL Jan 2021 - Current Website

Developed a personal website to showcase professional work. Learned the basic of frontend developing and shaped the product from sketches to high-fi prototypes all while maintaining a user-centered design.

### **CAT CAFE BOOKING SYSTEM**

Nov 2020 - Jan 2021 Booking App Rotterdam, NL

Designed a working prototype of a booking system for an adoption cat café in Denver, CO. Established business goals then designed and tested 2 solutions with real users to develop a product that is ready for investors.

### **GEO-BASED URBAN TRAVEL APP**

Case Study Rotterdam, NL May 2020 - Dec 2020

Designed an entire case study for a travel guide app to simplify the travel planning process. Benchmarked competitors and included real users from initial interviews to usability testing and final revisions. They shaped the product from sketches to high-fi prototypes and maintained a user-centered design. Mobile-first approach with a limited desktop variation.

### Other Experience

### **WORLD TRAVELS**

Independent Globe Feb 2019 - Nov 2019

Traveled the world to experience different cultures, ideas and people, which is how I came to live in the Netherlands. Learned invaluable communication skills when it comes to speaking in other languages and with non-native speakers.

### JUNIOR ARCHITECT

April 2018 - Nov 2018 ZP Architects & Engineers Denver, USA

Designed and researched a community market where I prototyped and presented ideas to stakeholders and users to find a solution that improved the area.

### JUNIOR ARCHITECT

Jan 2016 - Jan 2018 Hangar 41 Denver, USA

Sourced and created 12 proposals for new business opportunities which led to 2 new projects. Designed and prototyped over 25 projects which included client and consultant communication, research and project presentation.